Guide to the Frederick Herzog Papers, 1947-2011 and undated (bulk 1947-1995) RL.00536
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Research Files Series, 1947-2005 and undated (bulk 1960-1995), 37 Boxes
  Contains Frederick Herzog's research files and newspaper and magazine clippings on religion, civil rights, labor organizing, racial issues, protest in North Carolina and nationally, and other topics related to theology. Noteable materials document Herzog's involvement with the American Academy of Religion (AAR), his work with black churches and in Black Studies and theology, his work in Peru, and the relationship between the United Church of Christ (UCC) and the Evangelical Church of the Union (EKU) in Germany. Herzog's committee work in the Duke Divinity School and documents regarding various faculty matters, including faculty meeting minutes, are included in a Committees Subseries. The series is arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Angela Davis clippings, undated (Box 36)
  - Civil Rights clippings, 1964-1969 (Box 36)
  - Disability clippings, 1967-1973 (Box 36)
  - Duke Student Protest clippings, 1969 (Box 36)
  - Duke University racial/social issues clippings, 1961-1995 (Box 36)
  - Durham clippings, 1978-1996 (Box 36)
  - Housing Controversy/Operation Breakthrough clippings, 1965-1967 (Box 36)
  - Howard Wilkinson sermon and response clippings, 1969 (Box 36)
  - Miscellaneous Duke-Related clippings, 1968 (Box 36)
  - News clippings, 1970-1975 (Box 36)
  - North Carolina racial issues clippings, 1973-1983 and undated (Box 36)
  - Magazine clippings, 1961-1972 (Box 36)
  - Magazines, 1968-1978, 3 folders (Box 36)
  - Pamphlets, 1966-1978, 1 of 2 (Box 36)
  - Pamphlets, 1966-1978, 2 of 2 folders (Box 37)
  - Race relations clippings, 1960-1969, 2 folders (Box 37)
  - U.S. expatriates clippings, including letter from Herzog regarding conscientious objection, 1970 (Box 37)
  - Wilmington 10 clippings,1977-1978 (Box 37)
  - Altizer, Thomas, God is Dead, undated (Box 37)
  - American Academy of Religion (AAR), 1970-1996
    - American Academy of Religion (AAR), Euro-American Studies, 1986-1995, 3 folders (Box 37)
    - American Academy of Religion (AAR) Euro-American Studies consultation, 1987-1991 (Box 38)
    - American Academy of Religion (AAR), Euro-American theology, 1987-1994 and undated, 3 folders (Box 38)
    - American Academy of Religion, Euro-American theology readings, 1985-1992 and undated (Box 38)
    - American Academy of Religion (AAR) Session, G. Gutierrez on Las Cases, 1994-1995 and undated (Box 38)
    - American Academy of Religion (AAR) Liberation Theology Working Group, 1970-1989, 1 of 7 folders (Box 38)
    - American Academy of Religion (AAR) Liberation Theology Working Group, 1970-1989, 2-7 of 7 (Box 39)
    - American Academy of Religion Society of Biblical Literature Annual Meeting, 1996 (Box 39)
  - Animals, 1982, 1994 and undated (Box 39)
  - Application of MCCs to National Council of Churches Faith and Order Commission, 1978-1982, 1 of 2 (Box 39)
  - Application of MCCs to National Council of Churches Faith and Order Commission, 1978-1982, 2 of 2 folders (Box 40)
  - Art, 1977 and undated (Box 40)
  - Articles on liberation theology, 1999 and undated (Box 40)
  - Baptism, 1960 (Box 40)
  - Barth, Karl, 1947-1965, 2 folders (Box 40)
  - Karl Barth Colloquium, 1970 Dec. 4-5 (Box 40)
  - Bartolome de las Casas' Rebuttals to Emergent Theories of Spanish Empire, by Herman, Gale master's thesis, 1995 Apr. 11 (Box 40)
  - Bibliographies, 1993-1994 and undated (Box 40)
  - Black Church Studies, 1974-2000 (Box 40)
  - Black Church and Theology Studies, 1969-1995
    Consists of the Duke Divinity School's Herzog Project archival database, which is a printed index for subsequent folders of correspondence, class notes, research, and other materials about African American theology, the Black church, and African American studies at Duke. Original color coded has been noted below to assist patrons in using the index.
    - Herzog Project archival database (binder) with index to documents, undated (Box 71)
    - Black Theology (red folder), 1971-1973 and undated (Box 71)
    - Black Theology (green folder 1), 1973-1974 and undated (Box 71)
    - Black studies at Duke (green folder 2 part 1), 1969-1995, 2 folders (Box 71)
    - Black studies at Duke (green folder 2 part 2), 1969-1984 (Box 72)
  - Black history, 1973-2004 (Box 72)
  - Black theology, 1973 and undated (Box 40)
  - Bolivia Exchange Program, Erin Martin, 1995 (Box 40)
  - Brusseder, 1989-1992 and undated (Box 40)
  - Canon controversy at Duke, 1990 (Box 40)
  - The Challenge of Third World Culture, A Conference at Duke University, 1986 Sep. 25-27 (Box 40)
  - Christian Century reviews, 1958-1960 (Box 41)
  - Christian-Marxist dialogue (proposal), 1962-1969 (Box 41)
  - Christian Theology, 1993 (Box 41)
  - Church architecture, 1960-1965 (Box 41)
  - Church architecture, 1964-1970 (Box 41)
  - Church architecture (postcards), undated (Box 41)
  - Church of Pakistan: A Story of a Resurrecting Church, undated (Box 41)
  - Civil Rights timeline, undated (Box 41)
  - CLAY (Clergy and laity), 1978-1982 (Box 41)
  - Cobb, Jr., John B., How to say no to NAFTA, 1993 Nov. 10 (Box 41)
  - Cochabamba Instituto de Idiomas, 1992 (Box 41)
  - Columbus Year, 1992 (Box 41)
  - Communication, 1957-1967 (Box 42)
  - Conscience in Theology Today, Kirk Oldham masters project, undated (Box 42)
  - Covenant Discipleship (Methodist prayer groups), 1982-1984 (Box 42)
  - Covenant Discipleship Supplement, Good New to the Poor? The United Methodist Church's Abandonment of the Poor by Steven Manskar, undated (Box 42)
  - Covenant Discipleship Quarterly and Field IV Seminar on Ched Myers, Binding the Strong Man, 1990-1991 and undated (Box 42)
  - Criminal justice issues, 1974-1984 (Box 42)
  - Cuba, 1985-1987 (Box 42)
  - Detroit Theology in the Americas Conference, 1975, 3 folders (Box 42)
  - Divinity School Black Studies, Franklinton Center, 1969-1972 (Box 42)
  - Doctrine of God (Mission House), 1950s (Box 42)
  - Documents of the early 1970s on issues of theology, power, and race, 1970-1973 (Box 43)
  - Duke-Bonn relationship, 1984-1985 (Box 43)
  - Duke Divinity News and Notes, 1995-2001 (Box 43)
  - Duke-UNC Latin American Studies, 1989-1995, 3 folders (Box 43)
  - Duke University: Program in Latin American Studies working paper series, 1994 Apr. (Box 43)
  - Ecology, contra war, drug problems in U.S. and Latin America, 1989-1990 (Box 43)
  - Economics and Economy, 1993-1995 (Box 43)
    Especially in Latin America.
  - Economics and Theology Covenant Group, 1981-1982 (Box 43)
  - Ecumenical documents, 1954-1989 (Box 44)
  - El Salvador and other social concerns, 1976-1991 (Box 44)
  - Environmental Justice, 1986-1997 (Box 44)
  - Ethics, social, 1958-1961 (Box 44)
  - Evaluation of Herzog's Liberation Theology, 1973-1989 (Box 44)
  - Evangelisches Kirchenlexicon (EKL), 1986-1989 (Box 44)
  - Evangelism (relation to worship), 1959-1963 (Box 44)
  - Farmworkers, 1973-1981 (Box 44)
  - Feminism/women's liberation, 1973-1995 (Box 44)
  - Food/hunger, 1959-1984 (Box 44)
  - Frederick Herzog floppy disks (removed to Duke's electronic records server), undated (Box 45)
  - The Free Men by John Ehle, 1965 (Box 45)
    Annotated copy.
  - Full Communion Training, 1984-1995 and undated, 2 folders (Box 45)
  - Gastarbeiter (guestworkers) in Germany, 1971 (Box 45)
  - German Democratic Republic, 1972-1981 and undated (Box 45)
  - German Democratic Republic (East Germany under communism), undated (Box 45)
  - Gewissen (conscience), 1980-1981 (Box 45)
  - Globalization, 1992-1997 (Box 45)
  - Globalization of theology education, 1978-1995 (Box 46)
  - God-walk, 1987 (Box 46)
  - Goodwill industries, 1968-1971 (Box 46)
  - Goodwill and Operation Breakthrough, 1965-1968 (Box 46)
  - Graduate school matters, 1990-1995 (Box 46)
  - Greensboro shooting, 1979 (Box 46)
  - Gulf crisis, 1990-1991, 1 of 2 (Box 46)
  - Gulf crisis, 1990-1991, 2 of 2 folders (Box 47)
  - Handicapped/homeless, 1959-1995 (Box 47)
  - Hauerwas, Stanley: sermons and speeches, 1989-1994 and undated (Box 47)
  - Heidelberg Catechism, undated (Box 47)
  - Herzog's miscellaneous notes, undated (Box 47)
  - Himnario Quechua Metodista, 1988 (Box 47)
  - Holocaust, 1991-1995 (Box 47)
    Especially Duke, Nov. 1991.
  - Holy Spirit, 1992 and undated (Box 47)
  - Homosexuality metropolitan churches, 1971-1989, 2 folders (Box 47)
  - Hösch, Siegfried, "Theologische Ausbildung im Überlebenskontext Erfahrungsbericht von der Communidad Bíblico Teológica (CBT), Lima, undated (Box 47)
  - Howard University conference, 1974-1990 (Box 47)
  - Human Rights, 1993-1995 and 2011 (Box 47)
  - Humor, 1958-1986 (Box 48)
  - Hungertuch, 1986 (Box 48)
    Hunger-cloth.
  - Interdenominational dialogues, 1958-1986 (Box 48)
  - Interview with Wolfgang Schrage and correspondence, 1984-1988 (Box 48)
  - Jesus, 1988-1992 and undated (Box 48)
  - Judaism/Jews and Christians, 1958-1986 (Box 48)
  - Justice Church and Paul Lehmann, 1979-1982 (Box 48)
  - Kohler Strike, 1955-1959, 2 folders (Box 48)
  - Koinonia and similar communities, 1969-1980 (Box 49)
  - Labor Unions, 1970-1977 (Box 49)
  - La Costra Nostra: study group in Tübingen, and trip to Czechoslovakia, 1971-1972 (Box 49)
  - Latin America Press, Lima, 1994-1995 (Box 49)
  - Latin American Studies and working group, 1980-1995 (Box 49)
  - Latin American working group, Duke-UNC, member list, undated (Box 49)
  - Liberation Church, 1971-1982 (Box 49)
  - Liberation Theology, 1970-1989 (Box 49)
  - Liberation Theology and the Promise of the Church, Conference at Duke, April 1978, 2 folders (Box 49)
  - Lutheran Reformed Dialogue, 1978-1982 (Box 50)
  - Meeks, Douglas, 1969-1989 (Box 50)
  - Methodism, 1960-1989 (Box 50)
  - Methodists churches in Latin America, undated (Box 50)
  - Miscellaneous documents, 1960-1961 and 1990 (Box 50)
  - Miscellaneous Theology in the South, 1957-1972 (Box 50)
  - Mission House, 1952-1973, 2 folders (Box 50)
  - Modern Christian Thought from the Enlightenment to Vatican II by James C. Livingston, 1971 (Box 50)
    Contains Herzog's annotations.
  - Moltmann, Jürgen, "Lateinamerika - Land der Widersprüche" and letter, 1991-1995 and undated (Box 51)
  - Murray, Pauli, "Frederick Herzog on Liberation Theology," 1976 Apr. 17 (Box 51)
  - Nachrichten Einer Neuen Welt, 1946-1948 (Box 51)
  - Native Americans, 1956-1983 (Box 51)
  - Newsletters, 1975-1983 (Box 51)
  - Nicaragua/Contras/Witness for Peace, 1987-1988 and undated (Box 51)
  - Nineteenth-Century Theology Working Group newsletter, 1974 Feb. (Box 51)
  - North Dakota: Members of the Ashley Congregation, 1951-1973 (Box 51)
  - North Dakota Reformed Church issues, 1951-1952 and undated (Box 51)
  - North Dakota and Wisconsin churches, 1947-1965, 2 folders (Box 51)
  - Notes about the Columbus anniversary, 1992 (Box 52)
  - Osborn, Robert, "The Rise and the Fall of the Bible in Recent American Theology," undated (Box 52)
  - Pacifism, 1957-1962 (Box 52)
  - Panizo, Rosanna, 1984-1992 (Box 52)
  - Peace, 1970-1995, 3 folders (Box 52)
  - Peace Movement in the GDR (East Germany), 1980s (Box 52)
  - Peace (Vietnam War), 1966-1981 (Box 52)
  - Peru, 1958-1997
    - Gutiérrez, Gustavo, 1984-1997 (Box 52)
    - Iglesia Metodista del Peru, 1988 (Box 52)
    - Kirk, Robin, "Of the Shining Path" (Peru), 1992 Mar. 22 (Box 52)
    - Methodist Education in Peru: Social Gospel, Politics, and American Ideological and Economic Penetration, 1888-1930 by Rosa del Carmen Bruno-Jofré, 1988 (Box 53)
      Contains annotations and notes.
    - Methodist history of Peru, 1992 and undated (Box 53)
    - Peru, 1986-1994, 5 of 8 (Box 53)
    - Peru, 1986-1994, 6-8 of 8 (Box 54)
    - Peru, 1989, 3 folders (Box 54)
    - Peru, Andean region, 1990 and undated (Box 54)
    - Peru bibliography, 1992-1993 and undated (Box 55)
    - Peru Calling publication and Peru miscellaneous, 1958 and 1992-1993 (Box 55)
    - Peru: CBT (Comunidad Biblica Teologica Methodist Seminary), 1989-1995 (Box 55)
    - Peru/CBT/Basel Mission, 1990-1994 (Box 55)
    - Peru Conference, 1991 Oct. 14-16 (Box 55)
    - Peru, drug war, 1989-1991 (Box 55)
    - Peru and Duke/UNC Latin American Studies (mostly 1994), 2 folders (Box 55)
    - Peru in the media, 1985-1989 (Box 55)
    - Peru, J. Iquiñez paper, 1995 (Box 55)
    - Peru/Latin America articles, undated (Box 55)
    - Peru (Sendero, MRTA, Human Rights), 1989 (Box 56)
    - Peru summary (by Kristin Herzog), undated (Box 56)
    - Peru trips, 1987-1992 (Box 56)
    - Pontificia Universidad Católica del Peru ingres, 1989 and Iglesia Metodista del Peru, Acta de la Reunion de Consulta, 1989 Mar. 17-18 (Box 56)
  - Pictures, 1948-1949 and undated (Box 56)
  - Pietism research, 1967-1978 undated (Box 56)
  - Poems, etc., 1956-1982 and undated (Box 56)
  - Politics and religion, 1958-1967 (Box 56)
  - Prayer, 1959-1984 and undated (Box 56)
  - Prayer and Contemplation Groups (Div. School), 1984-1986 (Box 56)
  - Preaching and sermons, 1959-1982 (Box 56)
  - Principles of Christian Theology by John Macquarrie, second edition, 1966 and 1977 (Box 56)
  - Prison reform, 1973 (Box 57)
  - Prisons, 1960-1992 (Box 57)
  - Psychology, 1961-1980 (Box 57)
  - Race relations Durham/Duke, 1960-1965 and undated (Box 57)
  - Race relations sit-in, 1963-1964 (Box 57)
    Includes newspaper clippings of 1964 sit-in.
  - Réforme issue, 1948 Sep. 11 (Box 57)
  - Relationship of the Seminar Class to the German Church, 1992-1993 (Box 57)
  - Religion, 1955-1962 (Box 57)
  - Religious Socialism issues, Spring and Fall 1994 (Box 57)
  - Report on research, 1962 May 11 (Box 57)
  - Research grants, 1970-1984 (Box 57)
  - Research travel, 1972 (Box 57)
  - Resistance covenant as justice covenant, 1987-1989 (Box 57)
  - Resurrection, 1961 (Box 57)
  - Reviews of Herzog's work, 1951-1990, 1 of 2 (Box 57)
  - Reviews of Herzog's work, 1951-1990, 2 of 2 folders (Box 58)
  - Sauter, Bernard, 1985-1986 (Box 58)
  - Science and religion, 1962 (Box 58)
  - Seagroves, criminal case in Durham, 1993 (Box 58)
  - The Seminar Class, 1974-1984 (Box 58)
  - Seminar Class (Adult Sunday School) at Pilgrim United Church of Christ, founded in 1974 (still existing in 2011 under the name "Inquirers"), Herzog's Teaching of Theology to Lay People, 1976-1992 (Box 58)
  - Seminar and lecture agendas, 1969-1973 (Box 58)
  - Sin, 1963-1973 and undated (Box 58)
  - Social concerns and involvement, 1955 and 1963-1993, 2 of 3 folders (Box 58)
  - Social concerns and involvement, 1955 and 1963-1993, 3 of 3 folders (Box 59)
  - Socialism (Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee), 1968-1985 and undated (Box 59)
  - "The Social Philosophy of Jean-Frédéric Oberlin (1740-1826)" research statement1967 (Box 59)
  - Sound teaching, 1976-1986, 2 folders (Box 59)
  - Speaking engagements, 1962-1981, 2 folders (Box 59)
  - Spiritual formation, 1989-1995 (Box 60)
  - Spiritual formation covenant discipleship groups, 1986-1992 (Box 60)
  - Spirituality, 1982-1984 and undated (Box 60)
  - Systematic and contemporary studies list of scholars, undated (Box 60)
  - Teach the Book by Gustavo Gutiérrez Las Casas: In Search of the Poor of Jesus Christ, 1993 (Box 60)
  - Teología Aymara, undated (Box 60)
  - Theological Education and Liberation Theology, 1989-1992 (Box 60)
  - Theological Education and Liberation Theology (consultation 1978) (Box 60)
  - Theology in the Americas, 1975, 1 of 2 (Box 60)
  - Theology in the Americas, 1975, 2 of 2 folders (Box 61)
  - Theology in the Americas, 1975-1979, 4 folders (Box 61)
  - Theology in a global context, 1987-1988 and undated (Box 61)
  - Theology and Policy Program at Duke, 1972-1975, 3 folders (Box 61)
  - Theology of hope consultation, 1968 (Box 62)
  - United Church of Christ-Evangelical Church of the Union (UCC-EKU), 1961-1995
    Files with year titles contain various documents regarding the relationship between the UCC and EKU, including essays and writings, material regarding the activity of the working group such as meeting minutes, and other research of and communications between participants.
    - Consultation in Process Between EKU and UCC, "Toxic Injustice and the Integrity of God's Creation," 1987-1988 (Box 62)
    - Consultation-in-process (EKU-UCC) and resistance commitment, 1986-1988 (Box 62)
    - Discussions about the nature and task of the United Church of Christ, 1983-1995 (Box 62)
    - Dokumentation, 2006 Jan. 10 (Box 62)
    - Toxic Injustice and the Integrity of God's Creation conference, Divinity School, 1988 Oct. 14-15 (Box 62)
    - EKU-UCC Binder I, 1978-1979, 2 folders (Box 62)
    - EKU-UCC Binder II, 1979-1980, 2 folders (Box 62)
    - EKU-UCC, Catechism Project, 1994-1995 (Box 63)
    - EKU-UCC and Interdenominational Conversations, 1972-1989 and undated (Box 63)
    - EKU-UCC minutes, 1981-1991 and undated (Box 63)
    - EKU-UCC Newsletter, 1996 Nov. (Box 63)
    - EKU-UCC Relations, 1980-1995, 2 folders (Box 63)
    - EKU-UCC Relations, 1990-1991 (Box 63)
    - EKU-UCC visit of vicars, 1982 (Box 64)
    - EKU-UCC writings, undated (Box 64)
    - Exchange between Pilgrim United Church of Christ and United Church of Christ in Durham; 25 year anniversary of the United Church of Christ; and anniversary of the "exchange" in 2007, 1979-2007 (Box 64)
    - Germany/USA, undated (Box 64)
    - Herzog's work for interdenominational connections (ecumenism), 1988 (Box 64)
    - Interaction between EKU and the UCC, 1987-1988 (Box 64)
    - Relationship of the United Church of Christ to the Evangelical Church of the Union in West/East Germany, 2 folders (Box 64)
    - UCC commission on Christian unity, 1961-1962 (Box 64)
    - UCC disciples of Christ relations, undated (Box 65)
    - UCC-EKU Working Group, 1978 and 1998 (Box 65)
    - UCC relationship with German Evangelical Church of the Union (EKU), 1978-1986 (Box 65)
    - UCC statement of faith I, 1955-1959 (Box 65)
    - UCC statement of faith II, 1957-1959 (Box 65)
    - UCC southern conference, 1988-1989 (Box 65)
    - UCC 1983 peace work with East and West German churches, 1982-1984 (Box 65)
    - 1976-1978, 2 folders (Box 65)
    - 1976-1993 (Box 66)
    - 1978-1990, 2 folders (Box 66)
    - 1979-1982, 2 folders (Box 66)
    - 1980-1984, 1 of 2 (Box 66)
    - 1980-1984, 2 of 2 folders (Box 67)
    - 1980-1994 and 2003, 3 folders (Box 67)
    - 1981-1986 and undated, 2 of 4 (Box 67)
    - 1981-1986 and undated, 3-4 of 4 folders (Box 68)
    - 1982 (Box 68)
    - 1983-1985 (Box 68)
    - 1984-1995 (Box 68)
    - 1984-1998, 2 folders (Box 68)
    - 1987-1990 and undated (Box 68)
    - 1978 and 1990-1992 (Box 69)
    - 1984 and 1992-1994, 2 folders (Box 69)
    - 1994-1995 (Box 69)
  - United Methodism and American culture conferences, 1993-1994 (Box 69)
  - Vaage, Leif, 1989 and undated (Box 69)
  - Willie Jennings - for History of Black Studies Office of the Divinity School, 1971-1992 (Box 69)
  - World Council of Churches, 1956-1983 and undated (Box 69)
  - World Council of Churches (WCC) Meeting, Montreal, 1963 (Box 69)
  - Worship and church architecture, 1962-1966 (Box 69)
  - Zachau, Elga on EKU-UCC, 2005 (Box 70)
  - 1970s documents, 1973-1975 (Box 70)
  - Committees Subseries, 1960-1995
    Contains correspondence, minutes, membership lists, agendas, and newsletters related to Frederick Herzog's committee and faculty work.
    - Arts committee, Divinity School, 1981-1988 (Box 70)
    - Discussion of the nature of the Divinity School and of the curriculum, 1985-1995 (Box 70)
    - Divinity School faculty discussion of Bailey-Fulkerson Conflict & homosexuality issues, 1994 (Box 70)
    - Divinity School faculty matters, 1965-1995 (Box 70)
    - Divinity School faculty matters, 1973-1984 (Box 70)
    - Duke Divinity Inclusiveness Committee, 1991 (Box 70)
    - Faculty reaction to sit-in participation, 1964 Jan. 14 (Box 70)
    - Franklinton Center (Civil Rights struggle), 1969 (Box 70)
    - Graduate School committee, Duke Divinity curriculum, and faculty matters, 1969-1995 (Box 70)
    - Inclusiveness International Studies Committee, 1982-1995 (Box 70)
    - International Studies Committee proposal, Divinity School, 1995 Jan. 4 (Box 70)
    - Social Action Committee ("Christian Social Action"), 1960-1994 (Box 70)
- Writings and Speeches Series, 1948-1999 and undated (bulk 1950-1995), 9 Boxes
  Contains drafts and copies of Herzog's writings and speeches. Much of the material is comprised of his sermons and meditations. Also contains manuscript drafts of Herzog's publications, including drafts of Liberation Theology. The series is arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Articles and lectures, 1961-1995 and undated, 4 folders (Box 73)
  - Articles/sermons, 1974-1993 and undated (Box 73)
  - "Beginning at Home," 1978 Jan. (Box 74)
  - Bibliography-Herzog, 1999 (Box 74)
  - Chapel talks, Wisconsin and Duke, 1953-1966 (Box 74)
    Includes material for talks.
  - Christian Witness and a Sit-In, [1964?] (Box 74)
  - Drafts of speeches/lectures in mostly German, 1987-1988 (Box 74)
  - Earliest Herzog publications, 1954-1969 and undated, 2 folders (Box 74)
  - Edwards Eulogies, 1969 and 1994 (Box 74)
  - "The Engine of the Liberation Process: The Conference or the Revolution?" Review of Theology in the Americas, eds. Sergio Torres and John Eagleson (1976), undated (Box 74)
  - Ethics of resistance draft speech, undated (Box 74)
  - EKU-UCC "Politische Theologie im amerikanischen Raum," undated (Box 74)
  - Evangelische Kommantare, 1995 Aug. (Box 74)
  - Facing Ourselves, Palm Sunday sermon in Duke University chapel, 1966 Apr. 3 (Box 74)
  - Festschrift for 70th birthday, 1992-1995 (Box 74)
    Herzog never knew about this.
  - Funeral sermon for Mrs. Edwards, widower of William Edwards, 1993-1994 (Box 74)
  - The Future of Black Theology and other sermons, 1987-1985 and undated (Box 74)
  - Handwritten essay, 1948 and undated (Box 74)
    In German.
  - Important speeches/sermons of the 1980s, 1983-1989 (Box 74)
  - Introduction of Justo Gonzalez, Lilly conference, undated (Box 75)
  - Lectures, 1980-1982 and undated (Box 75)
  - Liberation Theology in the South and Detroit Conference on Theology in the Americas, 1980 and undated (Box 75)
  - Liberation Theology: Liberation in the Light of the Fourth Gospel, Frederick Herzog, 1972 (Box 75)
    Herzog's copy with some minor annotations.
  - Open letter to highschool friends who survived the war, 1947 Aug. (Box 75)
  - Political Theology essay and syllabus, 1968 and undated (Box 75)
  - Publications (mostly 1960s), 1960-1986 (Box 75)
  - Publications that contain articles by Herzog, 1959-1993 and undated, 2 of 5 (Box 75)
  - Publications that contain articles by Herzog, 1959-1993 and undated, 3-5 of 5 folders (Box 76)
  - Publications that contain reviews by Herzog, 1962-1983, 2 folders (Box 76)
  - "Reformed Tradition," undated (Box 76)
  - Research ou angels (Basel), 1948 (Box 77)
  - Sermon book, undated (Box 77)
    Probably all from the 1950s.
  - Sermons, 1950s-1960s (Box 77)
  - Sermons, 1974-1983 (Box 77)
  - Sermons and meditations (some in German),, 1961-1984 and undated, 2 of 3 (Box 77)
  - Sermons and meditations (some in German),, 1961-1984 and undated, 3 of 3 folders (Box 78)
  - Sermons and meditations, 1965 (Box 78)
  - Sermons, meditations, prayers, 1965-1982 and undated (Box 78)
  - Synopsis of The Eclipse of Biblical Narrative, by Hanse W. Frei, undated (Box 78)
  - Theological Seminary of the Mission House catalogues and bulletins, 1954-1959, 2 folders (Box 78)
  - Various sermons and meditations (German and English), 1991-1992 (Box 78)
  - Vom Hugrigen Menschen, Amos 8,11.12, 1952(?) (Box 78)
  - "Who Speaks for the Animals?" in "No Other Foundation," 1982 Winter (Box 78)
  - Wirtschaftswunder Oder Gemeinschaftswunder? Matthew 22, 1-14, Evangelische Kirche, Bad Honnef, 1993 June 20 (Box 79)